<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>World Statistics Day 2015</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/feed/"/>
  <id>https://worldstatisticsday.org/</id>
  <updated>2015-09-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>
  
  <rights>Copyright © 2015, World Statistics Day 2015</rights>

  <entry>
    <title type="html">Palestinian Central Bureau of Statistics will hold an international event to celebrate World Statistics Day 2015</title>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/2015/09/24/Palestine-Statistics-Day/"/>
    
    <id>/2015/09/24/Palestine-Statistics-Day</id>
    <published>2015-09-24T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-09-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>World Statistics Day 2015</name>
      <uri>https://worldstatisticsday.org/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:base="https://worldstatisticsday.org/" >
<![CDATA[

<p>The <a href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/files/WSD_PS_2015.pdf" target="_blank">Palestinian Central Bureau of Statistics(PCBS)</a> will celebrate this year’s World Statistics Day by organizing an international event that highlights emerging issues and challenges in official statistics. With this, the PCBS builds on the successful international conference PCBS it organized on the first World Statistics Day on 20 October 2010.</p>

<p>This year’s conference will consist of activities and events that highlight the role of official statistics to the progress of society. The event will witness the launching of the regional Code of Practices (COP). It will also highlight the <a href="http://unstats.un.org/sdgs/" target="_blank">Sustainable Development Goal indicators</a> from different views and perspectives, emphasize future core competencies in National Statistics (i.e. data visualization, utilization of big data, spatial data), discuss strategies to cope with information revolution and focus on advance innovation and analysis.</p>

<p>The conference will include reputable keynote speakers, panel discussions, data visualization shows, videos and much more. Conference participants will experience World Statistics Day with a Palestinian flavor with field trips to Palestinian historical and religious sites. Participants will include representatives of Arab and International Statistical Institutions, as well as international experts in the field of official statistics in addition to official research institutions as well as local and international media agencies. The Conference will be held at the Palestine Red Crescent Society HQ in Ramallah from 19-22 October 2015.</p>



]]>
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title type="html">Germany puts the focus on users with the launch of a new portal</title>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/2015/09/24/Germany-Statistics-Day/"/>
    
    <id>/2015/09/24/Germany-Statistics-Day</id>
    <published>2015-09-24T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-09-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>World Statistics Day 2015</name>
      <uri>https://worldstatisticsday.org/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:base="https://worldstatisticsday.org/" >
<![CDATA[

<p><a href="https://www.destatis.de/DE/Startseite.html" target="_blank">Destatis</a>, Germany’s national statistical office, will launch its new online portal “StatistikCampus” on 20 October this year. The portal is a special service focusing on users from academia featuring data for research, public use data as well as relevant services and events.</p>

<p>To foster statistical literacy, Destatis, in cooperation with the <a href="http://www.dstatg.de/" target="_blank">German Statistical Society (DStatG)</a> will organize a conference <a href="http://www.dstatg.de/de/startseite/aktuelle-news/article/24-wissenschaftliches-kolloquium-statistik-verstehen-orientierung-in-der-informationsgesellschaf/" target="_blank">“Understanding Statistics”</a> on 19-20 November 2015. The conference will provide a forum for a dialogue between official statistics and their users from academia, government and the private sector. During the conference, Destatis will also honor the winners of this year’s <a href="https://www.destatis.de/DE/UeberUns/UnsereAufgaben/GerhardFuerstPreis/GerhardFuerstPreis.html;jsessionid=9C8FF1C087EE24A655D2749A80100D03.cae4" target="_blank">Gerhard-Fuerst-Preis</a>. The Gerhard-Fuerst-Preis is awarded annually for outstanding Ph.D., master and bachelor theses in the area of official statistics.</p>



]]>
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title type="html">Hari Statistika Dunia will be celebrated in Indonesia</title>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/2015/09/22/logos-Indonesia/"/>
    
    <id>/2015/09/22/logos-Indonesia</id>
    <published>2015-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>World Statistics Day 2015</name>
      <uri>https://worldstatisticsday.org/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:base="https://worldstatisticsday.org/" >
<![CDATA[

<p><img src="https://worldstatisticsday.org/logos/id/WorldStatsDay_Logo_ID_b.jpg" alt="World Statistics Day 2015 logo in Indonesian" style="width:200px" /><br /><br />
Hari Statistika Dunia or World Statistics Day can be now celebrated in Indonesia with our logo newly available in Bahasa Indonesia, the official language of Indonesia. Submissions in any language are welcome. Please send them to <a href="&#109;&#097;&#105;&#108;&#116;&#111;:&#115;&#116;&#097;&#116;&#105;&#115;&#116;&#105;&#099;&#115;&#064;&#117;&#110;&#046;&#111;&#114;&#103;">&#115;&#116;&#097;&#116;&#105;&#115;&#116;&#105;&#099;&#115;&#064;&#117;&#110;&#046;&#111;&#114;&#103;</a></p>



]]>
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Swiss Statistical Society will celebrate World Statistics Day with a seminar on "Better data. Better lives."</title>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/2015/09/22/Swizerland-Statistics-Day/"/>
    
    <id>/2015/09/22/Swizerland-Statistics-Day</id>
    <published>2015-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>World Statistics Day 2015</name>
      <uri>https://worldstatisticsday.org/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:base="https://worldstatisticsday.org/" >
<![CDATA[

<p>To celebrate the second World Statistics Day and to further strengthen its visibility, the <a href="http://www.stat.ch" target="_blank"> Swiss Statistical Society</a> is organizing an event on 20 October 2015.</p>

<p>The seminar will take place at the Fachhochschule Nordwestschweiz in Olten, Switzerland, and will run from 13:30 - 18:30. Presenters include users and producers of statistics from the Swiss Federal Statistical Office, academia and the private sector. The full programme can be found <a href="http://www.stat.ch/docs/20151020_Programm_WorldStatisticsDay.pdf" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>



]]>
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title type="html">European Central Bank will celebrate World Statistics Day with a conference entitled "European Statistics by the European System of Central Banks"</title>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/2015/09/22/ECB-Statistics-Day/"/>
    
    <id>/2015/09/22/ECB-Statistics-Day</id>
    <published>2015-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>World Statistics Day 2015</name>
      <uri>https://worldstatisticsday.org/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:base="https://worldstatisticsday.org/" >
<![CDATA[

<p>To celebrate this year’s World Statistics Day, the <a href="http://www.ecb.europa.eu/stats/html/index.en.html" target="_blank">European Central Bank</a> is organizing and hosting a conference on the “European Statistics by the European System of Central Banks”. The main purpose of the conference is to present the European economic and financial statistics by the <a href="https://www.ecb.europa.eu/ecb/orga/escb/html/index.en.html" target="_blank">European System of Central Banks (ESCB)</a>, achievements and further developments.</p>

<p>The conference will provide EU policy-makers, senior statisticians from central banks around the world, academics, colleagues from other European and international institutions,representatives of the media and of banking and business associations with an opportunity to reflect on a number of key topics related to statistics produced by the ESCB. More information on the programme and registration details can be found <a href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/files/20151020_ECB_WSD_Programme.pdf" target="_blank">here</a> and <a href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/files/20151020_ECB_WSD_registration.pdf" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>



]]>
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title type="html">Turkish Institute of Statistics to celebrate World Statistics Day</title>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/2015/09/21/Turkey-Statistics-Day/"/>
    
    <id>/2015/09/21/Turkey-Statistics-Day</id>
    <published>2015-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>World Statistics Day 2015</name>
      <uri>https://worldstatisticsday.org/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:base="https://worldstatisticsday.org/" >
<![CDATA[

<p>The <a href="http://www.turkstat.gov.tr/" target="_blank">Turkish Institute of Statistics (Turkstat)</a> will celebrate this year’s World Statistics Day in many different ways. On 20 October, Turkstat will hold a panel discussion on “Better data. Better lives.” focusing on the importance of reliable statistics.  The panellists are Izak Atiyas (from academia), Prof.Dr. Güngör Uras (a journalist) and Mr. Tarhan Erdem (from research). The event will take place at Turkstat. In addition, all 26 regional offices will organise similar panels in collaboration with universities.</p>

<p>The office also prepared a range of advocacy material, incl. an article on the “Statistical System of Turkey: Past, Present and Future”, an interview with the director of Turkstat on the development of the national statistical system and a speech of the director launching World Statistics Day. Turkstat is also preparing a special press release “Statistics on Statistics” for the special day. Publicity material such as notepads and posters will be distributed in October and one lucky school in Ankara will receive a visit from Turkstat staff and receive an IT donation.  A dedicated website will be released by Turkstat by the end of September.</p>



]]>
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title type="html">Hong Kong, China, celebrates World Statistics Day</title>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/2015/09/21/HK-statistics-day/"/>
    
    <id>/2015/09/21/HK-statistics-day</id>
    <published>2015-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>World Statistics Day 2015</name>
      <uri>https://worldstatisticsday.org/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:base="https://worldstatisticsday.org/" >
<![CDATA[

<p><img src="https://worldstatisticsday.org/images/wsdposter_HK.png" alt="Hong Kong, China, celebrates World Statistics Day" style="width:200px" /><br /><br />
To promote the <a href="http://www.censtatd.gov.hk/statistical_literacy/wsd2015/index.jsp" target="_blank">World Statistics Day 2015</a> and 2016 Population By-census, <a href="http://www.censtatd.gov.hk/" target="_blank">the Census and Statistics Department</a> took part in <a href="http://www.censtatd.gov.hk/pastprojects/bf2015/index.jsp" target="_blank">Hong Kong Book Fair 2015</a> held from 15-21 July 2015 at the Hong Kong Convention and Exhibition Centre in Wan Chai. </p>

<p>The Department’s booth was located at the General Books Pavilion and exhibited panels giving details of the World Statistics Day 2015 and the 2016 Population By-census. The Department received favourable responses from the public, as visitors came to the booth to try the e-questionnaire of the 2016 Population By-census and play a challenging interactive computer quiz game.</p>

<p>Another initiative in the context of World Statistics Day 2015 was the delivery of a statistical talk on <a href="http://www.censtatd.gov.hk/statistical_literacy/wsd2015/uits/index.jsp" target="_blank">“Understanding Innovation and Technology Statistics”</a> at the Lecture Hall of the Hong Kong Science Museum on 5 September 2015. The speaker, Ms Alvina KWAN, Senior Statistician, outlined the salient features of the innovation and technology statistics compiled by the Census and Statistics Department during the talk. </p>

<p>On 20 October, the Census and Statistics Department will jointly organise a public lecture with the <a href="http://www.hkss.org.hk/" target="_blank">Hong Kong Statistical Society</a> and <a href="http://www.edb.gov.hk/en/" target="_blank">the Education Bureau</a> in celebration of the second World Statistics Day. Session topics include: (1) Changing Trends of Hong Kong’s Population and the Demographic Challenges Ahead, (2) Better Data – Better Policies, (3) Statistical Finance: Everything you want to know but are afraid to ask. The event will be held from 14:30-16:30 at the Lecture Hall of the Hong Kong Science Museum. For more details please visit <a href="http://www.censtatd.gov.hk/statistical_literacy/wsd2015/public_lecture/index.jsp" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>



]]>
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title type="html">Statistics Views and  Wiley are sponsoring a data visualization competition</title>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/2015/09/20/Wiley-DataViz/"/>
    
    <id>/2015/09/20/Wiley-DataViz</id>
    <published>2015-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>World Statistics Day 2015</name>
      <uri>https://worldstatisticsday.org/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:base="https://worldstatisticsday.org/" >
<![CDATA[

<p><a href="http://www.statisticsviews.com/view/index.html" target="_blank">Statistics Views and Wiley</a> are sponsoring the Best Data Visualization Competition in recognition of World Statistics Day 2015.</p>

<p>The winner gets the choice of an Apple Sports Watch or $500 in Amazon vouchers. The focus for this year’s global celebration is official statistics. For this competition, which closes 3 October entries should present international data from across all the world’s continents. Entries will be judged by a panel of representatives from the ASA, Royal Statistical Society, and European Network of Industrial and Business Statistics. <a href="http://www.statisticsviews.com/view/WorldStatsDayComp.html" target="_blank">Click here</a> for eligibility and submission guidelines. The winner will be announced 20 October — World Statistics Day.</p>



]]>
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title type="html">World Statistics Day button popular at the Joint Statistical Meetings (JSM) in Seattle and the ISI World Statistics Congress (WSC) in Rio de Janeiro</title>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/2015/09/18/WSD-Buttons-JSM-ISI-Rio/"/>
    
    <id>/2015/09/18/WSD-Buttons-JSM-ISI-Rio</id>
    <published>2015-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>World Statistics Day 2015</name>
      <uri>https://worldstatisticsday.org/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:base="https://worldstatisticsday.org/" >
<![CDATA[

<p><img src="https://worldstatisticsday.org/images/ISI-WSC_Button_1.jpg" alt="World Statistics Day Button in ISI Rio" style="width:300px" />  <img src="https://worldstatisticsday.org/images/ISI-WSC_Button_2.JPG" alt="World Statistics Day Button in ISI Rio" style="width:300px" />  <img src="https://worldstatisticsday.org/images/ISI_WSC_Button_3.png" alt="World Statistics Day Button in ISI Rio" style="width:300px" /><br /><br /></p>

<p>Buttons promoting this year’s celebration of World Statistics Day (WSD) were a hot commodity at recent national and international meetings: Buttons were distributed at the <a href="https://www.amstat.org/meetings/jsm/2015/" target="_blank">2015 Joint Statistical Meetings (JSM)</a> in Seattle as well as the <a href="http://www.isi2015.org/" target="_blank">2015 ISI World Statistics Congress</a> in Rio. In Seattle, the buttons were handed out at the <a href="http://www.amstat.org/" target="_blank">American Statistical Association’s</a> booth in the heavily trafficked Exhibit Hall. Many JSM 2015 attendees were spotted around the convention center and on streets nearby sporting the WSD button. More than 6,800 people attended the largest gathering of statisticians in the world and were introduced to WSD 15 during the event.
The 60th World Statistics Congress took place in Rio de Janeiro. This bi-annual conference was attended by more than 1500 participants from more than 100 countries. Almost 1000 buttons were distributed at the <a href="http://www.isi-web.org/" target="_blank">ISI booth</a> and could be seen around around the Riocentro, where 1,250 papers were presented in 282 sessions.</p>



]]>
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title type="html">Statistics Canada invites staff to take trip to the future</title>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/2015/09/18/Canada-Statistics-Day/"/>
    
    <id>/2015/09/18/Canada-Statistics-Day</id>
    <published>2015-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>World Statistics Day 2015</name>
      <uri>https://worldstatisticsday.org/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:base="https://worldstatisticsday.org/" >
<![CDATA[

<p><a href=" http://www.statcan.gc.ca/" target="_blank">Statistics Canada</a> employees will be celebrating World Statistics Day in a special way. The agency invited their staff to submit their vision of the future of their agency and how it will look like in 2035. A group of selected employees will present to their co-workers their vision. The event will be broadcast to all Statistics Canada staff across the country. A reverse time capsule will be produced, so employees in 2035 can watch it during their own World Statistics Day celebration!</p>

<p>Statistics Canada will also be hosting a panel discussion in Ottawa on official health statistics. First, a presentation will provide an overview of the Canadian Health Measures Survey and its objectives, collection processes and dissemination strategy. A panel discussion with Canadian experts from the public and private sectors will follow, along with audience questions. The session will focus on how health data are being used to address important health research questions and to develop emerging health-related policies.
Of course, Statistics Canada is also busy with preparing support material for their events such as web and intranet sites, videos, and other communications pieces.</p>



]]>
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title type="html">American Statistical Association and the Association of Public Data Users to host webinar on "Statistics for the World of Open Data"</title>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/2015/09/18/ASA-Open-Data/"/>
    
    <id>/2015/09/18/ASA-Open-Data</id>
    <published>2015-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>World Statistics Day 2015</name>
      <uri>https://worldstatisticsday.org/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:base="https://worldstatisticsday.org/" >
<![CDATA[

<p>In commemoration of World Statistics Day, Mark Elbert of the <a href="http://www.eia.gov" target="_blank">Energy Information Administration (EIA)</a> and Jay Meisenheimer of the <a href="http://www.bls.gov" target="_blank">Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS)</a> will talk about the exciting innovate ways their agencies are making their data available to the public to make it more accessible, insightful, and appealing. Meisenheimer will discuss how BLS uses data visualizations to tell interesting stories about the labor market and economy and Elbert will discuss how EIA uses relational metadata to create a data-ecosystem of interlinked online query tools, interactive charts and maps, and a robust open data program. The event is cosponsored by the <a href="http://www.amstat.org" target="_blank">American Statistical Association</a> and the <a href="http://apdu.org" target="_blank">Association of Public Data Users</a>. For more information and to register go <a href="http://www.amstat.org/education/weblectures/index.cfm#SWOD" target="_blank">here</a> and <a href="http://apdu.org/2015/08/03/statistics-for-the-world-of-open-data/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>



]]>
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title type="html">Popular World Statistics Day button in Arabic and French</title>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/resources/promotional-button-escwa/"/>
    
    <id>/resources/promotional-button-escwa</id>
    <published>2015-09-17T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-09-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>World Statistics Day 2015</name>
      <uri>https://worldstatisticsday.org/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:base="https://worldstatisticsday.org/" >
<![CDATA[

<p><img src="https://worldstatisticsday.org/images/WSD_ESCWA_Buttons.jpg" alt="World Statistics Day buttons in Arabic and French" style="width:300px" /><br /><br /></p>

<p><a href="http://www.escwa.un.org/divisions/main.asp?division=sd" target="_blank"> Statistics Division of the Economic and Social Commission for Western Asia (ESCWA)</a> produces popular WSD button in Arabic and French.</p>

<p>Courtesy of the Statistics Division of ESCWA our popular World Statistics Day button is now available in two new languages. You may download the Adobe Illustrator files <a href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/logos/WSD_ESCWA_Final_Buttons.ai" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>



]]>
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title type="html">WSD Logo now available in Latvian and Macedonian</title>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/2015/09/17/logos-in-Latvian-Macedonian/"/>
    
    <id>/2015/09/17/logos-in-Latvian-Macedonian</id>
    <published>2015-09-17T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-09-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>World Statistics Day 2015</name>
      <uri>https://worldstatisticsday.org/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:base="https://worldstatisticsday.org/" >
<![CDATA[

<p><img src="https://worldstatisticsday.org/logos/lv/WorldStatsDay_Logo_LV_b.png" alt="World Statistics Day 2015 logo in Latvian" style="width:200px" /><img src="https://worldstatisticsday.org/logos/mk/WorldStatsDay_Logo_MK.png" alt="World Statistics Day 2015 logo in Macedonian" style="width:200px" /><br /><br />
Our friendly World Statistics Day logo is now also available in Latvian and Macedonian. With the release of these two versions we can now say “Better data. Better lives.” in 21 languages. Keep sending us your translations to <a href="&#109;&#097;&#105;&#108;&#116;&#111;:&#115;&#116;&#097;&#116;&#105;&#115;&#116;&#105;&#099;&#115;&#064;&#117;&#110;&#046;&#111;&#114;&#103;">&#115;&#116;&#097;&#116;&#105;&#115;&#116;&#105;&#099;&#115;&#064;&#117;&#110;&#046;&#111;&#114;&#103;</a>!</p>



]]>
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title type="html">2015 marks the bicentenary of the birth of George Boole</title>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/2015/09/17/Ireland-statistics-day/"/>
    
    <id>/2015/09/17/Ireland-statistics-day</id>
    <published>2015-09-17T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-09-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>World Statistics Day 2015</name>
      <uri>https://worldstatisticsday.org/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:base="https://worldstatisticsday.org/" >
<![CDATA[

<p>In its resolution declaring 20 October 2015 as <a href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/2015/06/03/general-assembly-resolution/" target="_blank">the second World Statistics Day</a>, the United Nations General Assembly noted that this year also marks the bicentenary of the birth of George Boole, whose work on the application of the principles of logic as a form of algebra underpins modern computer science. A new 58-minute film commissioned by <a href="http://www.ucc.ie/en/" target="_blank">University College Cork </a>shines new light on the legacy of George Boole, recognised as the forefather of the information age.</p>

<p>The huge impact of George Boole’s work on technology today is explored in <a href="http://www.georgeboole.com/film/" target="_blank">The Genius of George Boole</a>, a stunning new film narrated by Oscar-winning actor Jeremy Irons and produced by multi award-winning Oxford Film and Television.  It assembles academics and industry leaders from across the globe to explore the life and importance of one of the world’s greatest unsung heroes.</p>

<p>World-renowned film producer and Ireland’s digital champion, Lord Puttnam, sets film with the question: “Is George Boole important?” Puttnam continues: “I guess, no George Boole, no Google, no Amazon, no Intel…that makes him pretty important,” leaving no doubt that Boole is indeed a key figure in our digital age. Dealing with the themes of genius and what motivates genius, the film looks at Boole’s legacy with special references to how Boole research has been applied in today’s world. The film also touches on the historic contexts of Ireland, Cork and UCC as well as England in the early nineteenth century.</p>

<p>The film, which was recently shown on national television in Ireland, will be shown at the United Nations HQ in New York on World Statistics Day courtesy of the <a href="http://www.ucc.ie/en/" target="_blank">University College Cork</a> in cooperation with the <a href="https://www.dfa.ie/pmun/newyork/" target="_blank">Permanent Mission of Ireland to the United Nations</a>.</p>



]]>
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title type="html">Puerto Rico Institute of Statistics is organizing "Expo Estadisticas 2015" in observance of the World Statistics Day 2015</title>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/2015/09/16/PuertoRico-statistics-day/"/>
    
    <id>/2015/09/16/PuertoRico-statistics-day</id>
    <published>2015-09-16T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-09-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>World Statistics Day 2015</name>
      <uri>https://worldstatisticsday.org/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:base="https://worldstatisticsday.org/" >
<![CDATA[

<p><img src="https://worldstatisticsday.org/images/PuertoRico_statistics_day_2015_poster.png" alt="Puerto Rico Statistics Day poster" style="width:300px" /><br /><br /></p>

<p><a href="http://www.estadisticas.gobierno.pr/iepr/Inicio.aspx" target="_blank">Puerto Rico Institute of Statistics</a> is a recently-minted independent public entity, with the mission of ensuring timely and universal access to comprehensive and reliable statistics on Puerto Rico. “Expo Estadisticas 2015”, a one day fair devoted to statistics, fits in the strategic plan of helping improve official data and statistics by bringing together students, teachers and professionals to discuss this important issue. Those interested can register <a href="http://www.estadisticas.gobierno.pr/iepr/Sobrenosotros/Quehacemos/Actividadesoficiales/ExpoEstadisticas2015.aspx" target="_blank"> here </a>.</p>



]]>
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title type="html">Philippine Statistical System celebrates World Statistics Day and the 26th National Statistics Month in October</title>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/2015/09/16/Philippines-statistics-day/"/>
    
    <id>/2015/09/16/Philippines-statistics-day</id>
    <published>2015-09-16T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-09-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>World Statistics Day 2015</name>
      <uri>https://worldstatisticsday.org/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:base="https://worldstatisticsday.org/" >
<![CDATA[

<p><img src="https://worldstatisticsday.org/images/26th_NSMposter.png" alt="Philippines Workshop banner" style="width:300px" /><br /><br />
Spearheaded by the <a href="https://psa.gov.ph" target="_blank">Philippine Statistics Authority </a>,<a href="http://nap.psa.gov.ph/pss/default.asp" target="_blank">the Philippine Statistical System </a> has developed a rich programme to celebrate their <a href="http://nap.psa.gov.ph/nsm/26thNSM/default.asp" target="_blank">26th National Statistics Month </a>and the Second World Statistics Day this October.</p>

<p>Celebration on the national level features an exhibit of Official Statistics in the Philippines, a Statistics Fair and the release of an audio-visual presentation on the milestones of the <a href="http://nap.psa.gov.ph/pss/default.asp" target="_blank"> Philippine Statistical System</a>. Streamers, tarpaulins and posters promoting the <a href="http://nap.psa.gov.ph/nsm/26thNSM/default.asp" target="_blank">26th National Statistics Month </a> and 2nd World Statistics Day will be displayed on the facades of government buildings across the country.</p>

<p>The exhibit of Official Statistics in the Philippines is aimed at showcasing the equipment, survey questionnaires, publications, advocacy materials used over the years, as well other information on the history of the statistics and statistical operations in the country. The exhibit will be on display in the Philippine Statistics Authority (PSA) Office in CVEA Building (Quezon City) throughout the month of October. The statistics fair aims at increasing public awareness on statistics as well as promoting the statistics profession among students as well as increasing appreciation among government planners about statistics’ importance in planning and decision-making.</p>

<p>Other planned national and local events include: symposia, a photography contest and a statistics quiz. You can find more details on these an many other interesting activities <a href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/files/WSD_Philippines_Activities.pdf" target="_blank"> here </a>.</p>



]]>
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title type="html">Former U.S. Labor Statistics Commissioners to be inducted into Labor Hall of Honor on World Statistics Day</title>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/2015/09/15/USA-wsd-programme/"/>
    
    <id>/2015/09/15/USA-wsd-programme</id>
    <published>2015-09-15T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-09-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>World Statistics Day 2015</name>
      <uri>https://worldstatisticsday.org/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:base="https://worldstatisticsday.org/" >
<![CDATA[

<p>The <a href="http://www.dol.gov/" target="_blank">U.S. Department of Labor</a> will induct <a href="http://www.bls.gov/home.htm" target="_blank">Bureau of Labor Statistics</a> Commissioners <a href="http://www.bls.gov/bls/history/commissioners/wright.htm" target="_blank">Carroll D. Wright</a> and <a href="http://www.bls.gov/bls/history/commissioners/norwood.htm" target="_blank">Janet L. Norwood</a> into the <a href="http://www.dol.gov/dol/aboutdol/hallofhonor/" target="_blank">Labor Hall of Honor</a> on Tuesday, 20 October 2015 at 11 a.m.</p>

<p>Carroll Wright was the first BLS Commissioner, serving from 1885 to 1905. Janet Norwood, who passed away recently, was the first woman to serve as BLS Commissioner and led the Bureau for 12 crucial years (1979-1991), modernizing it and raising the profile of its work. Both former Commissioners ensured BLS produced the high quality of statistics necessary to the proper functioning of a democratic government. This will be the first time BLS Commissioners will be inducted into the Labor Hall of Honor.</p>

<p>The Hall of Honor was established in 1988 to honor those Americans whose distinctive contributions in the field of labor have elevated working conditions, wages, and over-all quality of life of America’s working families. Recent inductees include former U.S. Senator <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EiRPjwRtOGg" target="_blank">Edward “Ted” M. Kennedy</a> and the <a href="http://www.dol.gov/dol/aboutdol/hallofhonor/2014_railroad.htm" target="_blank">Chinese Railroad Workers</a>.</p>

<p>During their time as Commissioner, Wright and Norwood each strongly emphasized the necessity of accurate data to help workers suffering from economic hardships. Their legacy lives on as the tangible results of their many accomplishments still impact workers today. On World Statistics Day, we look forward to honoring the achievements of both Wright and Norwood during the Hall of Honor Induction Ceremony.</p>



]]>
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title type="html">WSD logo now available in Estonian, Hungarian, Lithuanian and Welsh</title>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/2015/09/14/logos-in-welsh-estonian-hungarian-lithuanian/"/>
    
    <id>/2015/09/14/logos-in-welsh-estonian-hungarian-lithuanian</id>
    <published>2015-09-14T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-09-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>World Statistics Day 2015</name>
      <uri>https://worldstatisticsday.org/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:base="https://worldstatisticsday.org/" >
<![CDATA[

<p><img src="https://worldstatisticsday.org/logos/cy/WorldStatsDay_Logo_CY_b.jpg" alt="World Statistics Day 2015 logo in Welsh" style="width:200px" /><img src="https://worldstatisticsday.org/logos/et/WorldStatsDay_Logo_ET.png" alt="World Statistics Day 2015 logo in Estonian" style="width:200px" /><br /><img src="https://worldstatisticsday.org/logos/hu/WorldStatsDay_Logo_HU.jpg" alt="World Statistics Day 2015 logo in Hungarian" style="width:200px" /><img src="https://worldstatisticsday.org/logos/lt/WorldStatsDay_Logo_LT_b.png" alt="World Statistics Day 2015 logo in Lithuanian" style="width:200px" /><br /><br /> With the release of these four new versions, the logo of World Statistics Day 2015 is now available in 19 different languages. Feel free to use all of them, and become part of a truly global celebration on 20 October 2015. To get the logo in your language, please contact UNSD at <a href="&#109;&#097;&#105;&#108;&#116;&#111;:&#115;&#116;&#097;&#116;&#105;&#115;&#116;&#105;&#099;&#115;&#064;&#117;&#110;&#046;&#111;&#114;&#103;">&#115;&#116;&#097;&#116;&#105;&#115;&#116;&#105;&#099;&#115;&#064;&#117;&#110;&#046;&#111;&#114;&#103;</a> and provide the translation of all language in the logo into your language. UNSD in cooperation with the Graphic Design Unit of the UN will provide the logo in various file formats.</p>

<p>The World Statistics Day 2015 logo in different languages in available from <a href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/logos/">this link</a>. Is the logo in your own language already available?</p>



]]>
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title type="html">This is how World Statistics Day will be celebrated in Estonia</title>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/2015/09/14/estonia-wsd-programme/"/>
    
    <id>/2015/09/14/estonia-wsd-programme</id>
    <published>2015-09-14T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-09-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>World Statistics Day 2015</name>
      <uri>https://worldstatisticsday.org/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:base="https://worldstatisticsday.org/" >
<![CDATA[

<p><a href="http://www.stat.ee" target="_blank">Statistics Estonia</a> is planning a number of exciting events on and around 20 October to celebrate World Statistics Day 2015.</p>

<p>On the day itself, Statistics Estonia in cooperation with the <a href="http://www-history.mcs.st-andrews.ac.uk/Societies/Estonian_Statistical.html" target="_blank">Estonian Statistical Society</a> is organizing a one-day conference. The main office in Tallinn will open its doors to the general public and offer guided tours to visitors. Part of the tour will be a short presentation on the work of Statistics Estonia. Another great way to engage users will be a statistical quiz, which will be launched on the website of <a href="http://www.stat.ee" target="_blank">Statistics Estonia</a> on 19 October. The quiz will be available online throughout the week.</p>



]]>
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title type="html">Belarus celebrates 95 years of official statistics and World Statistics Day this year</title>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://worldstatisticsday.org/2015/09/11/belarus-wsd-programme/"/>
    
    <id>/2015/09/11/belarus-wsd-programme</id>
    <published>2015-09-11T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-09-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>World Statistics Day 2015</name>
      <uri>https://worldstatisticsday.org/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:base="https://worldstatisticsday.org/" >
<![CDATA[

<p>This year marks the 95th anniversary of Belarus’ <a href="http://www.belstat.gov.by/en/" target="_blank">Central Statistical Bureau (Belstat)</a>. To celebrate this anniversary and the second World Statistics Day, the Bureau has launched a series of contests and activities that promote and encourage user engagement.</p>

<p>A first contest, entitled “My profession is statistician”, provides young statisticians the opportunity to present their profession to the general public from their own view point and experience. A second, entitled “Statistics for All”, and invites students of the <a href="http://www.bseu.by/english/" target="_blank">Belarus State Economics University</a> to create infographics and analytical reviews that help make statistical information and insights accessible to everybody.</p>

<p>The Bureau is also organizing a “Day of Accessible Official Statistical Information” in the central office of BelStat as well as in the regional statistical offices. Secondary school students in their final year will get a special treat with a “Welcome Day” at Belstat. In addition, the Bureau is preparing a press release on the occasion of World Statistics Day 2015, and a new leaflet “Guide to the website of Belstat”. The World Statistics Day logo will feature prominently on the cover of various statistical publications of Belstat.</p>

<p>To reach as many users as possible, items about the celebration of the World Statistics Day will be included in agendas of thematic seminars and roundtables with users, respondents and academia organized by Belstat and Regional Statistical Offices over the next few weeks.</p>



]]>
    </content>
  </entry>

</feed>
